No fear. No limits. No equal.
Senna is a documentary film directed by Asif Kapadia.
The remarkable story of Brazilian racing driver Ayrton Senna, charting his physical and spiritual achievements on the track and off, his quest for perfection, and the mythical status he has since
attained, is the subject of Senna, a documentary feature that spans the racing legend's years as an F1 driver, from his opening season in 1984 to his untimely death a decade later.
Self (archive footage), played by Ayrton Senna.
Self, played by Alain Prost.
Self, played by Frank Williams.
Self, played by Ron Dennis.
Self, played by Viviane Senna.
Self (archive footage), played by Milton da Silva.
Senna is a 2010 documentary film that depicts the life and death of Brazilian
motor-racing champion Ayrton Senna, directed by Asif Kapadia.
The film was produced by StudioCanal, Working Title Films, and Midfield Films, and was distributed
by the parent company of the latter two production companies, Universal Pictures.
The film's narrative focuses on Senna's racing career in Formula One, from his debut in the 1984 Brazilian Grand Prix to his death in
an accident at the 1994 San Marino Grand Prix, with particular emphasis on his rivalry with fellow driver Alain Prost.
Unlike a traditional documentary, it has no formal commentary or retrospective "talking head" interviews, and relies primarily on
archival racetrack and broadcast news footage, voiceover narration, and home video clips provided by the Senna family.
Senna was acclaimed by critics.
At the 65th British Academy Film Awards, it won two BAFTAs for Best Documentary and Best
Editing, and also received a nomination for Outstanding British Film.
The film explores themes of sports car,
competition, champion, biography, rivalry.